So, you want to watch video on the web.
所以，你想在Web上看视频。
There are a bunch of standard APIs and protocols
有很多相关的API和协议
for getting moving images and sound into your browser.
使移动的图像和声音能够在你的浏览器上呈现
Sure, some of them are super high latency,
当然，他们中有些有超高延迟
and super high compression,
以及超高压缩
while others are super low compression
其他也有一些超低压缩
and super low latency.
以及超低延迟
But by and large, you can pick an operating point
但总的来说，你可以选择一个操作点
and find enough tooling to get 90 to 100 percent
并找到足够的工具，为你完成90%至100%的
of the job done for you. 11-p
的工作 11-p
Now, you decide to go the other way.
现在，你决定走另一条路
You want to ingest some video.
你想要摄取一些视频
Again, there are a bunch of APIs and protocols
也有很多API和协议
that will allow you to, well,
能够帮你
vary the compression ratios, and the latency,
改变压缩比和延迟
and the quality, and the reliability,
以及质量和可靠性
and the speed, and the realtime-ness,
以及速度和实时性
and a bunch of other things based on your needs,
以及其他你需要的事情
to get an ingest working.
来实现视频摄取
It's not quite as slick, but it works. 21-p
虽然没那么丝滑，但是能用。 21-p
Now, you want to add some production metadata
现在，你想要添加一些生产过程中的元数据
to the ingest and get it into your cloud production system.
将其摄取到你的云生产系统中
I normally class this sort of metadata as "exotic",
我通常将这种元数据归类为“外来物”，
because there are, well, loads of different types,
因为有很多不同的种类
and each type has typically got a tiny little usage,
每种类型都有很小的用途
and there are very few really good infrastructures
真正好的基础设施很少
or frameworks for solving the general case.
解决一般情况的框架也很少
I've seen mixes of Arduino and Raspberry Pi,
我看过Arduino和Raspberry Pi的混合
with RTP feeds over WiFi, with custom rate control,
通过WiFi的RTP实现馈送，可以自定义速率控制
and varying file types,
支持不同的文件类型
different ways of time... portrayal,
支持不同的时间方式
and different synchronizations, different error corrections,
不同的同步方式，不同的错误修正
and, meanwhile, the common problem remains the same. 34-p
但是，同样的问题还是存在 34-p
"I'd like to get this metadata from that thing,
我想得到元数据
over a timeline, onto my video and audio,
在时间轴上，在我的视频和音频上
while I'm shooting, and I want to be able to figure out
当我拍摄的时候，我想要能够知道
which metadata, from which device,
哪些元数据，是从哪些设备上来的
was associated with which take,
是哪一次拍摄的
from which camera, during the shoot."
用哪个相机拍摄的，在拍摄过程中
Simple, huh? 41-p
很简单吧？ 41-p
Well, none of this is really new.
这都不是新问题
We've been bundling these types of systems together
我们已经将这些类型的系统捆绑在一起
since the early days of cinema and television.
从电影和电视的早期开始
What's changed is that we now have the ability
已经发生的改变是，我们现在有能力
to pull vast quantities of data into a common cloudy store,
将大量的数据拉入公共云存储
and to play as much compute, and as much... stuff,
使用尽可能多的计算，尽可能多的...
as you can afford in the Cloud.
那些你能负担得起的云计算服务
The wonderful folks at Arri, Nablet, and TrackMen
Arri, Nablet和TrackMen的了不起的人们
helped put together some kit to explore the outline
帮助整理了一些工具来探索
of a generic solution, and we documented that piece of work
一些通用的解决方案，我们也记录这些工作
on the website mxf-live.io.
在一个地址为mxf-live.io的网站上
You can see that we captured some data
你可以看到我们捕获了一些数据
from the inside of the Arri camera,
从Arri相机的内部
as well as an external data feed of frog,
以及外部数据馈送
with the pan, the tilt, and the oar from the tripod head,
用三脚架头部的云台、水平仪和摇柄
encapsulated it into a standard file format,
将其封装为标准文件格式
we stuck it across the WiFi,
我们把它通过WiFi传送
and then serialized it onto the editor's timeline,
然后把它序列化到编辑的时间线上
so that we could do post-production on the live feed,
这样我们就可以在现场进行后期制作
with the captured metadata.
利用捕获的这些元数据
Great! Job done. 62-p
太棒了！搞定了！ 62-p
Not quite.
其实还没有
We figured out that there are really four
我们发现其实这里有
major sorts of metadata, split along two axes.
4种主要的元数据，可以分为两个轴
The first axis is pretty simple.
第一个轴很简单
Is it binary, or is it text?
是二进制的，还是文本的？
And this is important, 'cause that turns out
这很重要
to be a good predictor of how you're gonna process
因为这能够很好的预测你将如何处理
the metadata downstream.
下游的元数据
The second axis is where the data is isochronous.
第二个轴是数据等时的位置
In other words, one sample for each clock tick,
换句话说，每个时钟滴答声对应一个样本
every clock tick, or is it kinda lumpy,
每个时钟滴答声
with embedded timing? 74-p
都有一个嵌入的定时? 74-p
Let's look an example of metadata
咱们把每一个象限里的
for each of those quadrants.
元数据的例子都看一下
Isochronous binary is pretty common.
定时二进制是很常见的
That's the sort of thing that you'd find
你会发现
the position of the lens,
镜头的位置
sampled every chirp of its piezoelectric motor,
对压电马达的每一个声音进行采样
or maybe, sampled every frame.
或者对每一帧进行采样
Isochronous text, this might be, oh,
等时文本
all the Dolby Vision high dynamic range metadata property,
可能是所有Dolby Vision高动态范围元数据属性
stored as an XML document for every frame of the video.
视频每一帧都存储为XML文档
Blobs of binary data, this might be an event track,
二进制数据块，这可能是一个事件跟踪
signaling which smoke machine was turned on,
记录哪一台烟雾机被打开了
and at what time of day.
是什么时候打开的
Blobs of text data, well, this is pretty common.
文本数据，这是很常见的
That's exactly what closed captioning and subtitles are,
这就是封闭字幕
where each phrase of text is as labeled,
其中文本的每个短语都有标签
with the timing information for that phrase. 91-p
也带有该短语的时间信息 91-p
Once you've got these four fundamental types,
一旦你掌握了这四种基本类型
you can then look at transport.
你可以看一下传输
It helps to be able to store this timed data
它有助于存储这些定时数据
as a serializable stream of packets,
作为可序列化的数据包流
and for that we chose MXF,
因此我们选择MXF
because of the available infrastructure,
主要是考虑现有的基础设施
and the ability to represent clocks as rational numbers,
以及将时钟表示为有理数的能力
so the precise timing can be maintained
以便保持精确的计时
without the risk of drift if the systems are left running
如果系统保持运行，则无位移风险
for long periods of time,
在很长一段时间内
like weeks, and months, and years.
例如几周，几个月，以及几年
Those packets can then be mapped and layered
然后可以映射和分层这些数据包
with different transports, like WebRTC,
用不同的方式传输，例如WebRTC
to get them from where they are, to where they need to be. 105-p
把他们从现在的地方传输到需要的地方 105-p
And now, it starts to get interesting.
现在，要开始变得有趣了
Whilst MXF is pretty handy for the hardware
MXF对于硬件来说非常方便
and firmware layers, there are open source projects,
对固件也很方便，有很多开源项目
like OpenTimelineIO from Pixar, and the ASWS,
例如Pixar的OpenTimelineIO和ASWS
that are much more friendly for interacting
对互动来说更友好
with that data in a generic, product-independent way.
以通用的、独立于产品的方式使用这些数据
Having said that, we know that transcoding video is lossy,
话虽如此，我们知道转码视频是有损的
and transcoding metadata may actually destroy
而转码元数据实际上可能会破坏
its usefulness.
它的有用性
So, wherever possible, retaining the original,
所以，要尽可能的保持原始数据
possibly bulky, metadata in its original form, is vital,
可能体积庞大，但是原始形式的元数据至关重要
and computing simplified proxies for that metadata
计算元数据的简化代理
becomes important for visualization.
对于可视化非常重要
If you're going to do all of that in the general case,
如果你打算在一般情况下做所有这些
then managing identifiers of the metadata type,
然后管理元数据类型的标识符
and how it's associated with other assets,
以及它如何与其他值相关联
could become a complexity nightmare,
可能成为一场复杂的噩梦
unless you design some sort of common framework
除非你设计了某种通用框架
for associating elements, based on simple identifiers,
为关联元素，基于简单标识符
such as URIs. 125-p
例如URI 125-p
And that's as far as we've got.
这就是目前我们所能做到的
There's interest from studios, and vendors,
制片商和供应商对此感兴趣
and a whole bunch of people,
还有很多人也有兴趣
and I hope to put more time into it, personally,
我个人也希望能投入更多时间在这项工作上
when I pass on my role as SMPTE Standards Vice President
我将把我作为SMPTE标准副总裁的职位
to someone else in January,
在一月份移交给其他人
and if it interests you, then I'd love to talk.
如果你有兴趣，我愿意和你深入交流
I'm sure there is something here that the brain trust of W3C
我相信W3C的智囊团
and SMPTE can genuinely create something that's useful
和SMPTE能够为视频的世界和其他行业
for the world of media, as well as for other verticals.
真正创造出有用的东西
Thanks!
谢谢！